[SOUND]
[声音]
So we often use color in data visualization.
数据可视化中我们经常用到颜色
And it's important to understand how best to use color to trigger perceptual
懂得怎样最好地利用颜色来触发知觉线索
cues and other ways of sensing the data.
和其它感知数据的方式十分重要
These rules have come from Colin Ware's book on information visualization.
下面这些规则来自Colin Ware关于信息可视化的书
As we're picking out colors, it's often better to think of colors not in their
我们选择颜色时 最好不要按它们
component values that are used to store them in the computer, basically red,
储存在电脑中的组成颜色
green, and blue, or a certain portion of red, green, and blue.
即红 绿 蓝 或其按某比例的混合 来思考
It's better to think of them in a more natural set of three components.
而是要按另一组更自然的三种成分的表达方式
Basically hue, saturation, and value.
也即色相 饱和度和明暗度
Hue is basically where the color is in the color wheel.
色相就是某颜色在色轮上的位置
Is it red, yellow, green, cyan, blue, or magenta, or some place in between.
它可以是红 黄 绿 青 蓝 品红 或者它们之间的某颜色
Saturation is how intense a color is,
饱和度是表示色彩的强度
what is its distance from a dull grey to a vibrant version of that hue.
也就是从暗灰到那个色相某更鲜艳处的距离
And then value is how bright the color is, its distance from black.
明度则表示颜色有多亮 即它到黑色的距离
And so if you're given a color in RGB, there's a little bit of
因此当给你一个RGB表示的颜色时 这里有
code here that would show you what the color should be in HSV.
一小段代码来告诉你这个颜色如何用HSV表示
And a similar color space is used any time you're picking colors in applications.
你在应用中选择颜色时还会 用到一个类似的色彩空间
For example, in Microsoft applications you get this color space,
比如在微软的应用中你会用到这个色彩空间
where hue is shown horizontally
在这里色相是水平铺开的
as we go from red to yellow, to green, to cyan, to blue,
从红到黄 到绿 到青 到蓝
to magenta, and back to red, and then saturation is vertically.
到品红 再回到红 而饱和度在纵向表示
And we're moving from a gray through some muted versions of
我们可以从灰色移动到色相的不同饱和度处
the hues all the way to the full intensity versions of the hues here.
一直到色相的最大强度处
And so you're picking your hue and your saturation here in this space.
也就是你在这个空间中选择色相和饱和度
And then value is kind of denoted here,
而明度在这里体现
going from black to full intensity, and in this case it's going to white.
从黑色一直到最大明度 也就是白色
This isn't quite a value axis, but it's very closely related.
这其实不完全是明度轴 但跟明度紧密相关
So, hues as we've seen before, hues are a good choice for
正如我们见过的那样 色相是
representing nominal variables, for representing categories.
表示类变量 即表示分类的教好选择
And we've seen that five or ten hues are quite effective in visualizations.
在可视化中使用 5 或 10 个色相是十分有效的
You don't want to have too many colors.
你不需要太多的颜色
But five to ten different hues can be quite effective at denoting,
但用5到10个不同色相来代表
at mapping different values of a nominal variable.
来映射类变量的不同值效果甚佳
There's as many as twelve colors, twelve good colors that you can pick from
有12种不错的颜色供你选择
that are based on Ward's extension of some work by Berlin and Kay.
这是由Ware在Berlin和Kay的研究基础上扩展后得到的
And so, there's the main six colors, white, black, red, yellow,
首先是六种主色 白 黑 红 黄
green, and blue.
绿以及蓝
And these are uniformly chosen across cultures
在不同文化中 这些都是公认的
as being good different colors, basic colors.
颜色类别 或基本色
To that you can add six more colors.
在此基础上你可以增加另外六种颜色
Grey, pink, orange, brown, purple, and cyan.
灰 粉 橙 棕 紫和青
And so this is a good choice, starting with the first six and then picking colors
那么这些选项就不少了 先从开始的六种颜色选择
from the next six, if you need good colors to map to a nominal variable.
然后是后六个颜色 如果你需要用些好的颜色来映射类变量的话
Saturation is helpful when you're mapping various elements of a visualization.
饱和色在你需要在视觉化过程中 映射不同元素时很有用
You want to use fully saturated colors for small things in a visualization,
视觉化图表中尺码小的事物要用全饱和色
if you have a thin line, you want to use a fully saturated color.
如果你的图上有一条细线 你应该用全饱和的颜色。
It's easier to see this saturated red-orange and a saturated blue than
在这里完全饱和的红-橙色和 完全饱和的蓝色会比
a desaturated red-orange and a desaturated blue on these two lines.
未饱和的红橙色和未饱和的蓝色 容易看到
Both, with a white background, or a black background,
在白色的背景或者是黑色的背景下
it's still easier to see the saturated lines than the desaturated lines.
都是饱和色的线比非饱和色的线更容易被看到
You want to use desaturated colors for fills, so you want saturated strokes and
填充色 应该选用未饱和色 也就是 画线用饱和色
desaturated fills.
填充用未饱和色
And so here's bar graph with blue and orange using desaturated blue and
这是一张柱状图 用不饱和的蓝色和橙色
orange, you can still see the differences.
仍然可以区分得出
When you have saturated large fills, the aesthetic can be a bit harsh and
如果你用饱和的颜色来做填充 看起来就不那么美观 并且
also it could be a little bit distracting.
容易分散注意力
So it's better to have desaturated fills and saturated strokes.
所以框线用饱和的颜色 填充用不饱和的颜色比较好
It's also important to pay attention to contrast.
对颜色反差注意也很重要
You want to use brighter colors in order to gain attention.
要用较亮的颜色来吸取注意力
So here, for example I've got desaturated bars, and I've got one saturated bar
比如 这里有几个不饱和的柱形 和一个饱和的柱形
in case I want to draw attention to this particular data value in a visualization.
用饱和的柱形来表示需额外注意的数据
And then you want to pay attention to brightness contrast,
然后 你也要注意的是亮度的反差
not just color contrast.
而不只是颜色的反差
So, contrast means a difference.
反差代表着某种不同
Ordinarily contrast deals with luminance or brightness.
一般情况下反差对应的是明暗和亮度
And you look at the brightness of one color versus the brightness of another
如一个颜色的亮度对比另一个颜色的亮度
color, or
或者
the value of one color versus the value of another color.
一个颜色的明度值对比另一个颜色的明度值
But you also want to make sure there's good luminance contrast.
你也要注意保证的亮度差异恰当
Color contrast is often just a difference in hue, but
颜色差异经常只是色相的区别
not necessarily a difference in brightness.
不一定是亮度的区别
Here I've got orange text on top of a blue hue,
这里有一段橙色的文字呈现在蓝色相的底色上
and I'm just changing the saturation and
我只是改变
value of this blue hue from black to full intensity to white.
蓝色的色调从黑到白
And you can see that even though there's sufficient color contrast,
这里你能看到 即使颜色的反差足够大
there's differences in the color, there's not much difference in the brightness here
颜色完全不同 但是此处没有亮度反差
and it becomes very difficult to read.
然后阅读起来就很困难
And so you want to make sure you maintain good brightness contrast,
所以你要保证保持一个适当的的亮度反差
value contrast, in addition to just color contrast.
明度反差 来配合颜色的反差
So the recommended usage, you don't want to use colors
那么对于颜色使用 若是用于对相邻颜色的比较
to represent quantitative variables when you want to
你最好别用不同的颜色
measure the difference between neighboring values in a visualization.
来代表定量的数值
It is a good indication, we can use density to represent brightness or
好的迹象是 我们可以使用浓度来代表
value, and then we have saturation and hue.
明度或者亮度 然后 我们还有饱和度和色相
It is good for ordinal variables, so we can tell that one color is brighter
颜色用来标识顺序值是很好用的 我们可看到一个颜色比另一个颜色明亮
than another color, we can tell that one color is different than another color, or
人眼也很容易识别不同的两个或几个颜色
closer to, for example, red, or by different hues,
也很能识别当前颜色和某个基础色 比如红色 很接近
or we can tell that one color is more intense than another color.
也能识别当前颜色比另一个颜色更加浓郁。
So these are good for
所以即使我们肉眼不容易分辨颜色的区别到底有多大
ordinal variables even though we can't tell how much different they would be.
但是用颜色来表示这些有序的变量却很方便
And for categories, hue is an excellent choice for categories.
色相非常适合来表示分类
Changing the value or the brightness, or changing the saturation.
无论是调整颜色的亮度 还是调整饱和度
How grey a color is versus how intense is not as good
就是说调整颜色的灰度和颜色的浓度相比
a differentiator of categories.
不如类别一样好区分
So the horizontal axis of a bar graph,
所以一个柱状图的横轴
you don't necessarily want the bars to be going between grayer and
你未必需要用柱状图来表示不同灰度 或者不同亮度
brighter, but it is good to have them be different colors, different hues.
而是表示不同的颜色 或者色相
You can use color maps to represent quantitative values,
我们也可以用颜色图来表达数值化的值
and this is a very common thing to do.
这种用法很常见
We see it in weather maps all the time, for example,
比如在天气图中比较常见
when we're displaying the temperature in a geographic region.
如标识不同地理地区的温度
The choice of colormaps can be problematic.
颜色图的具体颜色选择可能会有潜在问题
And so as we saw before in this three-dimensional visualization,
我们之前在这个三维的图表中已经看到
we're just using an ordinary rainbow colormap.
我们用的只是一个普通的彩虹色图谱
It's darker here, it's a little dark here, and it's brighter here and here.
这里比较暗 这里也有点暗 这里和这里比较亮
And those changes in brightness in the colors chosen for
色谱中所选中的色彩的变化会和
the colormap can interfere with the perception of light and
图片中物体表面变化产生的明暗
shadow used to get the orientation of the surfaces here.
互相影响
And it looks like this blue area is darker than it should be by the shading.
那么看起来这块的蓝色会比它原始渲染的更深一些
And it looks like this skull has a divot here when it actually doesn't.
此处看起来这个头骨似乎有一个凹陷 但并不存在
So it's best to avoid brightness and saturation variations in a colormap for
所以最好避免使用亮度和饱和度的变化来渲染
illuminated three-dimensional objects.
亮度环境下的三维的对象
And in general, mapping brightness and
总体上来看 将亮度和饱和度配对到数值数据上相比
saturation to actual quantitative values is more error prone than hue maps.
使用色相更容易出错
So if this is a direct hue map, then it's easier for
所以如果这是一个简单色相图
us to make a reference into a legend for what those values are.
就更容易对应为那些数值的图谱了。
And this overcomes the problem hue would ordinarily have as a quantitative
这就克服了一般用色相来描述数据变量时遇到的问题
variable representation, because we have this legend here on the side.
因为在旁边有这个标有数值的图谱
So here's some examples.
这里有些例子
Two dimensions and three dimensions, and we seen the rainbow map is not
有二维的也有三维的 我们也已看到彩虹图对于
a very good choice for three dimensional data because of its light and dark values.
三维数据来说不是一个好的选择 在表示亮度或暗度的数据方面
But, in two dimensions it does a pretty good job of showing positive and
但在二维中对于显示正值或负值
negative values in this region.
效果还不错
A light to dark map is good for showing magnitude,
由亮到黑的图用来显示大小较好
not necessarily positive or negative here, but just magnitude here.
不一定是正数或负数 只是大小就可
And it's really a poor choice,
而后面这样的选择则是很糟糕的
you don't want to use luminance mapping to map variables that are plotted on
即如果用亮度来映射表示三维表面的数据
a three-dimensional surface because it really interferes with the lighting.
因为会和光的照明相冲突
So for a three dimensional surface, you want to try to pick some hue scale
所以对于三维的表面 你可以这样选择色调区段
that doesn't affect saturation or value of the color, so that the shading
使其不影响饱和度或色值
isn't affected by the mapping of the variable that is plotted over the surface.
这样阴影部分不会被三维表面的变量的映射所影响
And so in these two cases we have uniform brightness, uniform value and
在这两种例子中 在彩色图中 亮度 色值
saturation, well, at least uniform value across the colormap,
饱和度 等都是均匀的 至少色值是这样
and so it doesn't interfere with the lighting of a three-dimensional shape.
所以它与三维形体中光照不相干扰
Although, these aren't necessarily the best colormaps to use for two dimensions
尽管对于二维来说 这未必就是最好的彩色图
where you can get away with more of a change in luminance.
通过改变亮度基本就可满足要求
And there's a really good website for choosing colors called,
有一个很不错的关于选择颜色的网站
colorbrewer2.org, and I'd encourage all of you to take a look at that website.
就是colorbrewer2.org 我鼓励大家去看看
It's designed for picking color maps for geographical data.
是为地理数据选择彩色图而设计的
And I'll point you to it here and
我就告诉你在哪儿
encourage you to go take a look at it right now.
鼓励你们现在就看看
So we've learned that it's best to think of color for
我们了解到在数据可视化中使用色彩时
data visualization as being a hue, a saturation, and a value.
要从色彩的色相 饱和度和明度的角度来考虑
And we don't always want to choose a rainbow colormap
不一定每次都要使用彩虹色图谱
when we're displaying our data.
来显示数据
We want to look at what kind of data we're displaying and
我们要按照我们想要显示的数据类型
choose the best colormap for that data.
来选择最好的彩色显示图
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community